<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated with ArwicXmlEditor (09 Mar 2016 23:28) by Tim Ings-->
<TechnologyDataPack xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Name="Dominion Core Technology Data">
  <Technologies>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_AGRICULTURE</ID>
      <Description>The basis of all civilized life, Agriculture allows working the land for food. This, in turn, makes possible the whole concept of a group of humans establishing themselves in one permanent location and thriving there, instead of living as hunter-gatherers and constantly moving about in search of food. It allows Workers to construct Farms, which are vital for increasing the $(food) Food output of map tiles. All civilizations begin the game with this technology by default.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>0</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>0</GridX>
      <GridY>5</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_AGRICULTURE</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites />
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_POTTERY</ID>
      <Description>As the art of building objects from clay, Pottery is also a fundament of civilization, creating the means for long-term storage of food and materials and their protection from the elements. Thanks to that, a number of future developments are possible. This technology allows your cities to build the Granary, which provides $(food) Food, helping your cities grow larger. It also allows you to build the Shrine, the first $(faith) Faith-producing building in the game.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>35</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>1</GridX>
      <GridY>1</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_POTTERY</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_AGRICULTURE</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY</ID>
      <Description>A cornerstone of human development, Animal Husbandry allows the access to various animal resources via the Pasture. It also reveals Horses, the first Strategic resource in the game, which are used to build all mounted units. It also allows access to the first Trading unit in the game - the Caravan - and your first Trade route.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>35</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>1</GridX>
      <GridY>4</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_AGRICULTURE</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_ARCHERY</ID>
      <Description>Archery, the technology to develop the first ranged weapons, is one of the most important achievements of early human civilization. Inventing the bow allows you to build the Archer, the first ranged unit in the game.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>35</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>1</GridX>
      <GridY>6</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_ARCHERY</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_AGRICULTURE</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_MINING</ID>
      <Description>Mining develops the ability to extract mineral resources from the bowels of the earth. This is done via Mines - improvements which give access to a variety of mineral resources and increase the $(production) Production of map tiles. Also, the technology teaches Workers to chop down forests, allowing the construction of other improvements on those tiles.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>35</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>1</GridX>
      <GridY>8</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_MINING</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_AGRICULTURE</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_SAILING</ID>
      <Description>One of the great achievements of early civilizations, Sailing develops the means to travel the seas by building Triremes, and to access sea resources by building Work Boats. For now, your vessels can only travel in coastal waters. Sailing also enables access to the second Trade unit - the Cargo Ship - and to your second Trade route.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>0</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_SAILING</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_POTTERY</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_CALENDAR</ID>
      <Description>The invention of the Calendar allows your civilization to predict the approximate time of change of seasons - an ability essential for advanced agriculture. Your civilization can now work advanced crops, such as Sugar and Wine, and use their many benefits. This technology allows Workers to construct Plantations on many luxury resources, which are extremely important for $(happiness) Happiness and trade. (Note that many resources require you to have chopped a forest or jungle first, which requires other Technologies.) It also allows the construction of Stone Works in cities that have improved sources of Stone or Marble.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>1</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_CALENDAR</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_POTTERY</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_WRITING</ID>
      <Description>One of the cornerstones of civilization, Writing is the ability to transfer information to durable materials (stone, paper), and thus preserve it for the generations. It allows the beginning of the scientific development of your empire, by the construction of the Library, the first science building in the game. It also allows the establishment of embassies in other civilizations' capitals.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>2</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_WRITING</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_POTTERY</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_TRAPPING</ID>
      <Description>Some animals cannot be domesticated and grown in human-controlled environments - they need to be hunted in their natural habitats. The Trapping technology allows your Workers to build Camps for hunting on resources such as Deer and Ivory. Also allows the construction of the first $(happiness) Happiness-producing building, the Circus, in cities which have access to Horses or Ivory.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>4</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_TRAPPING</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_THE_WHEEL</ID>
      <Description>The Wheel is another key technology, which fundamentally changes the way humans move around and transport things. It allows Workers to construct Roads, an essential part of your empire's infrastructure, allowing units and cargo to move across the map faster. Also allows you to build the Chariot Archer, a fast and powerful ranged unit; and the Water Mill, which gives your city a $(food) Food and $(production) Production boost if it's next to a river.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>6</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_THE_WHEEL</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_MASONRY</ID>
      <Description>Masonry is the art of building massive stone structures, and working with stone in general. It allows you to build Walls, which greatly improve the defense of cities. Also allows Workers to construct Quarries to gain access to Stone and Marble resources, and clear marshes, allowing other improvements to be constructed on that tile.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>8</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_MASONRY</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_MINING</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
    <Technology>
      <ID>TECH_BRONZE_WORKING</ID>
      <Description>The first metal-working technology, Bronze Working provides your civilization with sturdy, durable tools and the first more serious weapons. It allows you to build the Spearman, a military unit strong against mounted enemies; and the Barracks, the first unit training building. It also allows your Workers to Chop down jungle, clearing the map tile so other improvements can be constructed. It also reveals the second strategic resource, Iron.</Description>
      <ResearchCost>55</ResearchCost>
      <GridX>2</GridX>
      <GridY>9</GridY>
      <IconKey>TECH_BRONZE_WORKING</IconKey>
      <IconAtlas>Core:XML/AtlasDefinitions/TechnologyAtlasDefinition</IconAtlas>
      <Prerequisites>
        <Prerequisites>TECH_MINING</Prerequisites>
      </Prerequisites>
    </Technology>
  </Technologies>
</TechnologyDataPack>